All right so I guess we're going to goes five o'clock
and I know there's a free beverages after this so I'm sure everybody is
had a long day lots of interesting sessions and is that you to kinda get on to
something more fun so I'll try to make this hopefully as interesting as possible?
So, my name is chris patterson and
...the program manager on the visual studio cloud services team which is kind of
fancy name for all of the various developer services plus t fs that we work
in the developer division at microsoft and I look after team build and the build
service on a visual studio online and I've been doing that for about.
Two-and-a-half years now so, before we get started on a quick show
of hands of who uses team build today anybody used to
...while a lot of people okay how many lovett.
Awesome that's good so.
Hopefully what I have to show you will make you like it a lot more than
you currently do and then over time we can make you actually enjoy working with it.
I do ask that you submit a.
...evaluation of the session afterwards so there's a price drawing in their
secure code and I'm sure you can find in your build apple where to go submit the evaluations.
All right so.
...quick...so I've got some kind of a
real quick intro and, we're talking about why we've done a lot of stuff
we've done I've got a whole bunch of demos and then some sort
of nitty-gritty details on architecture and things like that and if we finish up and,
have time obviously some queuing?
All right...with my big reveal all right so this is
visual studio online I'll be doing all my demos there and this is what's listed as the
build-up preview tab if...download the rc yet which you probably habits
of just came out you'll see this in the on from...just list of this way and then
in a couple of weeks you will see this also in your accounts envisions to
do online so one of the bigger differences obviously as I can now create a
build definition of the web.
Which is so, I no longer have to go and open up visual
studio...just going to build definition and for certainly cross platform developers
...a big deal additionally you'll notice that the build definition is a lot simpler than
it used to be so what I'm going to do is go and grab my?
Little consul application here and we'll just stick to build that solution
will save it or my cool.
Stuff.
You'll notice...actually popped up and ask me for commentwhich is a nice thing that we
did used to have dedicated to it and we're presented with
...quite different screen than we used to
...so one thing that is hopefully obvious years them was is gone?
Within this system so there's no windows workflow there's no
giant's able template to edit just...set up a build definition you put
together pretty simple sequential list of steps that just run various tools and
...and go from there so now we see the agents picked up the building
we're actually getting real time live consul output
from the agent running on a machine somewhere manager at this point.
So, anyway, so, there's a quick and dirty how you create a new build definition.
All right so.
There are lots of other questions
I'm sure later so that's a quick intro to the new experience.
So, one of the things that you it's obviously there is it's completely new
there is no shared code with the current system ...side-by-side with the current
ammo based ...in fact you see the language in the...you'll see
...build for what was currently
...build the current as of well yesterday and then
just build definitions for what we have going forward and
is a big change what we had a lot of reasons as to why we have to go that way so?
...like I said I've been doing this...a while now
...a lot of conversations with a lot of different customers and these are sort of some of the, you know,
things I get on a regular basis so like so I just...run a script after I run
...build how hard could that possibly be
...who's customized example template knows it's very difficult so that's we
...fix that next one is hey you have integration with insert tool or service here whatever
your tool of the day scripting language build tool...your
cloud service whatever and the answer almost always was no because that
company who wanted to do that had to go learn very specific domain specific language
and build the ll that hopefully was...to give the right...of assemblies and then
ship that to you somehow and then give you an explanation of here's how you go insert that
in your workflow template and some
did are certainly some companies of the but it was very difficult and we wanted to make that process a lot better.
Can I build my ios and android apps...dvs anybody struggling with
this now anybody doing ios android development and actually needs to build on say
...can't do it ok so we wanted to fix that?
The next one was what about my java app...a lot of the customers...lot of people who
...to fs they write big enterprise java apps or something
yeltsin.
You I could say well so golan microsoft build.
First.
And, then...integrate adding kind of a strange way and then,
yeah, you can kind of build your job...but it's not native right it doesn't feel right to them
...of this weird tool that if your java developer you don't want to go...misspelled it's not something you work on.
This is always a fun one so I get this every single release
it's also I created a new build definition based on that new template.
we still use twenty twelve or twenty ten or whatever was so I've got a make sure everybody has the latest release
of visual studio just at the build template.
Yep, sorry what happens when you serialized...object...and stored on a server than
try to do serialized later and maybe some of those types aren't there.
So, we had to fix that.
And, then this one this one's actually kind of close to my heart because as you saw we have a nice
...consul view right that
...build blog it's exactly the same thing you would see if you ran that to on the
command line or...know...the output of your tool into a text document
right it is the log you would expect to see it isn't sort of a weird mash up of
an xml tree which has bits and pieces of the output you expect to see which makes it
very difficult to debug when something goes wrong and that happens and build a lot.
And, then the final one which is
...sure somebody said this experience open example simple for the first-time.
You're kidding right.
So, anyway, so,
there's a lot of just the interactions that I've had personally with customers and
internal folks etc on using team build and.
For better for some people do like it obviously is very powerful but
are certainly going forward it is something we wanted to improve on as we set out to
kind of build this new version I put some pretty strong principles of
...the team one of the big ones my number one was I don't want to create another
build dsl there's lots of them out there they're great ones out there is
...build might be great but is there our shell people single like writing builds
empower shell on the across platforms side you might use grail for android development or
x code build for ios development or enter maven or any
one of a dozen others but the point is that is your...that should be your
build you can run that on your machine you can open up a command prompt you could open up your
id...you can run your build when you sort of abstract away from that which is kind of what happens with the same
...have this other dsl now this windows workflow example language that you
have to learn which abstracts you away in makes it very difficult to run your build on your
machineso,
I wanted to change that sort of overall premise we have to
support on windows platforms natively we must have a native across platforms story and we have that and
we will take a look at that I want to have
...intentional extensibility model meaning some very straightforward way for
you or some tool vendor or the community to create
a new tool run or task for the system and deliberate
...a way that you can install into your server...make use of very easily and then that last one
is my little pet peeves about the log.
So, anyway, those are some of the basics of why we started in how we
went about it so before I kinda go in and.
And, talk about the details of how...some of the more interesting ones I'm going-to.
Just go through some demos.
We kind of already saw the file new build my solution...state will take a little bit of a deeper
look at...what we did there so I said I my basic consul out
...go back and look at the build summary nothing particularly interesting on this one.
But, let's just go at...add something to it so that script example I gave well I
want to add running a batch script so on-the-go and pull
up this gallery of plug-in that we have a lot of interesting ones there.
Will pick the batch script?
One here close.
Simply move that up and say you...to run that just after
tess run and then I want to go pick.
The subscript that I've got in here.
again, very simple easy to set up I could add additional arguments there is a fair
bit of inline help here so, hopefully it's easy for you guys to get going and,
work with and there's a few other tabs we can walk through just to kinda get an idea of experience so that's
kind of adding a new step to your build click over
there is repository so here
there's a few interesting things listed so there's get obviously because
this is a get team project within visual studio online if you...in atf
...project you would see appropriate options there we also have
...support built-in forget hub that...will see when this goes live on the service
that's pretty cool because actually integrates with the web books and get hub so you get ci
for projects on get hub in visual studio online so that's something that's interesting to you.
Variables so this is another kind of one of those nice things
I've lots of times...I have this variable or this
password where this password we need to use during the build but what I put it so,
we fix that problem.
So, you say my password.
And, then we'll just puta few whatever here...icon enroll market out as a
lapses and now that is stored encrypted at rest on the server so,
you don't have to worry about...by getting it and when it's actually running
and decrepit runtime we do everything we can to mask
...log so it shouldn't be so somebody could always there's always a way to
copy a file somewhere but at least in the normal course of usage
...these things are well reasonably well secured?
Another big interesting change that people vast for...is, you know,
I've got to build definition set-up and I wanted
to have multiple triggers who has a problem you've got like at least two different
build definitions that do exactly the same thing that you need to keep in sake but one is scheduled in
...ci raise your hand right, yeah, that's a huge...so we
fix that and now I can set up and say because this is get I so we know what I want
include master and then I'm going to include everything that is like rafts.
Heads.
Star or feature.
Star so I want to make sure that.
Every time a feature branches...and gets the same
build definition just starts getting built obvious ci so that's kinda nice and, you know,
what I want to build to go off it
three-m let's say eastern standard time for master and then, you know,
...the fleet the and
then I'd also like one to go off at three am ...on top
one I don't know tokyo standard time whatever so with
the new flexibility here I can have ci on multiple branches
in the same definition I can also have multiple trigger set
up for multiple different timezones schedules on the same definition
so gives a huge amount of flexibility capability to your organization into your developers?
And, of course popping up asking for comment.
Donovan favorite feature.
All right so but, that save.
Go over to the next...so other general information here.
This is kind of what you...sort of just kind of hold all for settings but there's some other so
nice things here so listed here I actually have to
...other listed we'll get into what pools are here a little bit later
...which fool I want my build qtwo I put some descriptions
build number format used to that this thing here is really
interesting so does anybody work in an organization where they sort
of worry about the fact that the build agent is running...a process that
has pretty broad access to your...service right you run unit
test and that it can connect up so we fix that.
So, the way this works is
the build agent connects to your pool and on the server
...a credential the whatever the service account is running as only has to
permissions to listen to that pool that's it so it's a very low set and then we generate a
time bomb token at runtime that is either project
collection scoped meaning that token has access to all of the sort of data within the
project collection or project scoped so you can actually say hey this token can only read
stuff rewrites of out of this team project and it's not available generally
...environment for processes that are executing
so there's really no straightforward way for somebody to say write a unit test that then
...connection goes back into something of various so we've really tried to sandbox a lot of things
there to make that just better for you overall.
Timeouts pretty straightforward...infinite you can set this is a for hung builds
right if you want to say hey if the build ever runs more than an hour something's wrong to join killer for me.
Badge enabled this kinda goes with the get...thing...so you can get that little badge like if
you're doing ci from via so you have been...a little badge there and then the list of
demands, demands are there are two let-you control
which agents in your system can run particular build definition
so you might be from the tags...my use agent tags kind of in the system the, yeah,
there they've got some interesting problems because of the way the controller potentially schedules work on the
agents?
...the nice thing here is all this is handle by the server...much more complex you can say hey
...a value exist orders a name exist or doesn't even equal value so you have
more flexibility and you can use these demands to make sure like certain sets build
definitions are built on certain agents this is kind of useful if you want to say you have a pool of
ten agents and you want to...of say you keep a set of them hot for a particular
...of definitions so you want to make sure that one definition always runs on one set of
agent so the work spaces or the repositories already synched...
For you so it's kinda...
Retention policies we we've heard a lot of people that struggle
with the number based retention policy...have that problem.
The fact like
...my builds after ten kind of a pain so we changed it in this
one-on-one obvious to be here broad feedback on this one people start using it but now it's database so
you basically say hey I want to delete builds that are
older the next days again you have the same sort of filtering capability for branches you
can say hey branches that are feature branches I...to keep those around for like two
days for master we want ten for release maybe we want.
Whatever right.
The other thing you can do is the administrator on your server can sort of set of total maximum retention
policy that helps and keep it clean so this make sure that drops are cleaned up in the server data
...cleaned up so you don't have people retaining builds forever unless they mark
...explicitly mark them as retain forever.
That's retention policies and then the last one here.
Is auditing history so it's
been a common request to be able to see what changed your build definition
so-if you want-to see what changed you can just click on it and, sort of see the
...view of what change the who change that?
So, anyway, so, those are some of the...the
...lights we...some more interesting stuff just of like how to.
We've taken looked a lot of these come from the user...so I think six or
seven of the features we added are very high on the user voice request for team build so I think
we've done a lot to improve that all right so that's kind of the basic
build my solution basic definition.
The next one I want to talk about is deployment.
So, I have this ...in the forget...
And, measure real quick.
How many of you try to use the current sort-of continuous deployment stuff from via so?
Yeah, it's works nice for small stuff but quickly.
Runs into problems if you have anything more complicated so earlier today I have this app
that I deployed and it's a it's a really simple wanted not terribly interesting but it does
have to websites try to deploy to websites from the same repository in the
build definition the by successfully done that?
Anyway, so,
this morning or I set up a build definition does exactly that.
So, right here I've got a normal build solution we just
built my solution and then I just added another invocation of
microsoft build to just package up the website...it puts the command lines
...say hey generate a web deploys that forming and put it in this location so if you.
...a zoom...maybe in this a little bit.
So, I go here and look at the end.
There is a just a variable package location this variable we call
build staging directory which is well-known variable...system can also web so that puts
it there and then can...so api?
Puts it into different location which is which is kinda nice
...was really simple to go setups and I have to websites well how do I want to
...that...nice thing is you have.
...different options so.
Right here you'll see I've added the as your website deployment task is one of these tasks
that's built in and.
Here list the as your subscription
that I want to use for it and I give it some other parameters well one of the other
sort of challenges we had with the previous system was in people generally had
...to...your from an automated system is how do I do
with the credentials right I've got either the certificate file I need to
deal with or if you're kind of more forward your using
...or the staff and you've got like a user that
you created a service principle you created your...active directory to handle automated stuff how do I
do with that so we actually added support.
Into the system for something which is called service connections and there's a few different
ones so right now there's as
your chef and then generic what the as you're one when you
break it up you just give it some information you can get your subscription id the
subscription name the certificate or credentials right,
you know, you use the ad as
your account you can put in the credentials this does that exact same thing in fact.
What this task that's here does?
Is it just runs our shell?
So, is anybody using the as your our shell...for managing their
I love it I think it's great it's easy to automate it's easy to work with.
So, what we've done is this as your
service connection feature what it does in the system is it just simply registers that
...subscription on the machine as part of the automation then you can just run whatever our
shell you want to in this case we've got a canned our shell script
that is actually you can see it because all of the tasks that are listed here or on
...hub and...open-source you can see them
we should make it much easier to debug or to...the future
...just a camtasia our shell script right there?
That sets up the connection you pick the website location website name which
package and go it runs the deployment and then I just a second one right there.
In fact if you wanted to go a little more complicated for not complicated but a little
more full featured and you had your own deployment script.
That-you, that-you would written empower show you can simply just drop on the casual our
...task and.
Again, pick your subscription that you want to use that's register with the system and
then whatever scripts checked...source control so if you've already developed your app whatever it is
and you have a our shell script that deploys your application it's very easy to integrate those
for sort of this nice continuous deployment system.
All right.
So, that's how we're trying to make continuous deployment ...little more awesome
would go run these...take like three minutes four minutes to run...not as interesting.
So, the next thing that everybody asks me is
so I deployed my app and I would really love to smoke...
Right I want to do some sort of...it with a web...just...web and point to make sure
it up and running right now the problem so.
We've added into the system.
...so the by...with the...testing service and visually online...by use it
...ok so we actually have great integration without as well.
So, coming here with the system or task for just running cloud load tests
in this particular case just go ahead and q this guy real quick.
This is a cloud mode test the just what they call it
...quick protest and basically all it does.
You give it a url that you want the...tessa hit you give the user load and
...duration and they'll just kind of generate a web...low test on-the-fly in their system
for you but just...that url so you can see here it's...got sources and
it's now streaming data back and eventually it will finish up and
we'll be able to see the results we take a look at
minute so I could have taken this task pretty easily just...it to the end of
my build and I would have the ability to run a load test
...very straightforward as part of my continuous deployment build.
All right so that's continuous deployment becoming more awesome.
And, if you...donovan...your have...
Ok, so, there's a session not was a...
So, there's session cross platform...deliver if you didn't go to that you
watch the video there's stuff that's going to make it even better and
...future updates coming to via so into...
So, I was basically
...one-x the other thing I wanted to show you that's pretty cool about this is so,
by default this task is going to look and say okay I know I'm attached to a
via so account so I know I can just run a...low test right because it's part of my via so account what if
you're using dvs right you've got to have us on from would be nice to potentially take advantage of the
clobbered testing service integrated in will so you see here
this advanced section in there which is poorly name within...fix that but
basically what you could do here is you can give it a url for your via so account and
some credentials and it will use that to connect up in q upper cloud
...whatever up so even if you're on param you can use the cloud low
testy service to test your...from your on from server are
all integrates together really nicely there's a bunch of other stuff so if I kinda go
look here.
...some of the other test tasks so,
there's ones for actually deploying the test...
multiple boxes and running distributed tests obviously regular visual studio test
...test carbon which will get here in a minute and,
more will show up over time so this system is really extensible
is very easy for us to add features to it in help you take advantage...
All right so what's next.
What's go over here and take a look at.
Okay, so.
Here I have my...
And, I've got the cross
platform agent running as part of our commitment to
making sure we can build everything you need to we have an agent that is written
...node js that is also open-source that runs on other platforms
non windows platforms so we actually I had a guy set one up on raspberry
pi I thought that was really interesting not sure raspberry...be the best villager but
...I've seen we've got some people that deployment doctor containers but one of the things
we want to do and we'll do coastguard...is actually put out a
doctor container imager base image with our agent on it so if you're using
doctor you can easily spin up agents on your linux machines of course it runs
fine automatic which is what I have it running here and that's also available and get up there.
But, anyway, Iusing the new template just the vary basic right here x
code build template that we ship out-of-the-box I set of my
build for this little ios application and,
the tests as well now in this particular deployment test publishing is not there.
Oops sorry honey to pick the.
Pick the right pool are the hosted
pool does not all so that was actually interesting that I should have shown that to you will show it later.
It actually the pop-up came up...from...this build to a
pool that didn't have any machines that was that were available had no maxim apple...just the hosted
...that only has windows machines currently so, that's kinda how the demands work so this particular
...definition demands x code all of the agents...a bunch of capabilities
of what they can do so the system tries to make sure that you don't inadvertently
...a build to an agent that can't handle it so-if iq this guy up.
Can bring up the?
Low-energy here just to show it's real and
you can see the agent running starting the build.
Running through building rx code project next code test
what we decided to do and now tester probably up in launching of course on the simulator?
So, that was my testnot super interesting behave
there we actually by default...you...exes tool which is
...utility that actually facebook develops it gives
you much prettier consul output and also will publish your
x code test results to...
a format which we now natively understanding can import into the test
just results system so you get...complete integration of that build run unit
tasks with your iowa's builds now as well.
So,...moving through pretty quick.
All right so let's go back to here.
Right so...okay so what do we do we've got.
Building a solution we've taken care of a bunch of the difficulties hey you
want to run a script you want to add something...bill that's easy
your multiple schedules multiple triggers your history.
Better retention policies lots of significant improvements.
So, that should that should make things really nice but what if you want to sort of take full
advantage of other services remember I talked about a...have integration with service
x well one of the things that you will see that's not sure if it's been announced
by...or not but.
We have done work with salmon and, they did a lot of work to integrate
...make building examine base steps really easy and this new system so this is
an example of examine android app and it actually there's,
there's also a template zimmer dot android zimmer dot ios right here for setting
up and it just sets up in builds my basic solution
it takes care of things like...nicely...actually will work with our hosted build
services well so when you use the...build system with the hosted pool you can
...did all of this...tools are pre installed there and we will keep them up to date along with
...so you can actually start taking advantage of even that service with your examine windows
android apps we don't have maxima hosted...pool yet we'll see
over time if that happens but really simply you set up...your salmon license you have to
activates...license activation is right there integrated...you don't have to do any funky stuff on
the build machine you just put in whatever the account appropriate account is for license
activation we build restore new get packages
...imis build.
And, then the salmon test cloud and here it here are actually win up
all I had to do was go up in this...test crowding create
...right how to create and app and, it gives me all of the information
will be a tutorial coming out on thisbut,
I just put in my api key which again is nicely stored here
as a hidden secret variables so we don't see that?
Given the device I...which...tell where the test assemblies
are and, it's going to go ahead and take care that for me so I can go
...this build and this one does really take a little while because.
It's doing a bunch of stuff but...it's done.
And, you go up and look at.
...test...account you can
see right here all of the nice test details I can look at this particular
...which are ran early this morning gives me this really nice kind of
view as to what failed I can click in here and I can see that ok so I
had a failed step here so...want to do is...and via so.
For my.
For my failure so.
Complete integration into nc we set up and run we can run your
...we can run your tests by integrating well with the
salmon test cloud on multiple different devices of different types different form factors
different west versions and then when you get failures is really easy to
pipe that data back into your software development process and via so by just simply logging a bug so,
really trying...build-out that ecosystem in and make your tools easier for you to use?
So, that's our...integration so current is going through
and activating license and will finish that up at some point?
And, then finally.
Are we talked a bit about the
java so in here I've got a little to do list which is a java app
it just runs maven because that's what I used to build this java app but the other thing
here listed is published results and currently and
...was animal if I want to run some other unit test framework right I've got
to...either...for the visual studio test runner system
are kinda somehow get it jerry rigged in and then I've got
to figure out how to turn the xml from that test framework into this
...thing which is a very interesting format as well to get it kind of published up so I get
...nice integration well with this new extensibility model system
we actually were opening that up to make it a lot easier so here?
You can see I've got support for easily publishing
...test results from a...xml and unit xml vs
test tr x of course and then x unit...is coming up shortly so it
makes it very easy for you to basically take enron whatever test framework you
wantbecause almost all of them whether it's mocha or I don't know what cucumber
or some other sort of interesting test framework for some other platform.
All of them pretty much boil down to generating j unit and unit actually
for us it's crx but it makes it very easy to integrate those things in so you can
publish those test results and of course when they run if I go back and actually look at one of these builds.
Right on the summary page I...list of all of the test results
there I see of course the commits I...click on that it's going to open
...this test run for me and the test
run explore in via so now instead of having...visual studio and...actually give
me some nice analysis and details of what happened in that test run and what
...what failed etc very easily?
All right so that is.
Kind of the just of what we built right it's
much more extensible it's much more open should be much simpler and
should be very leave the our in your hands to work with largely
the tools the frameworks languages you want to work with but we're just going to run it?
All right so.
Go back to powerpoint and talk about some of the details.
We already talked about node to build dsl.
Right so this is kind of this is actually you'll notice the...today's a little bit different than this
one I took the screenshot a couple months ago but
it is broad set of various different technologies...will continue to grow
from both from us I don't know if you saw when I had it up there was one
for deploying to chef there's a darker task in there so,
really making...available to integrate with the tools that you use today.
So, by tag line...don't make me learn yours just run mine.
Native cross platform.
...js based the agent that runs on macro
...linux...primarily retested on a...to so...over
time will keep testing on other frameworks but basically runs wherever node runs.
So, far we that's been pretty good we have lots out-of-the-box
sport for common technologies that you use on various different
...platform frameworks of course it's open-source so you can go see it
...will be taking contributions if you sofeel
...to fix a barbour implement a feature.
...extensibility...first thing
...first-place I focus on extensibility is you saw it really easy to add a task to say
run a script.
Right hey run our shell script...command script run some random
...that integrate with we set a whole bunch of environment variables for
you to make it easy to get information like what's the build number what's the what's the
agent name what is the...the...fs url if that's something you want
to know...a lot of those things are set...environment variables so makes easy to
grab from your script we monitor exit codes and we even have
some formats that you can use to send other information the system to update the build number
two log progress to write...
order to publishing artifact so-if you want-to say run a script that create some file
that-you...then have uploaded to the drop for...there's a
very easy command we call it that you can which is just a standard out string
...you can pass to say hey publish this file as part of the drop for me will take care of it?
However, if you do want to do some extensibility or integrate some service
the model is basically a json file with a script that
you create a zip from...upload it to the server and that's automatically distributed to
all the agents right so it's very straightforward in fact the
agents themselves sort of auto update...same mechanism so as...agent
...get published to the service or your server the updates all the agency your build
lab automatically restart themselves and update themselves to the latest bits
...you from having to go out to a hundred build machines and go install them.
All of our tasks or open-source out there we
figured out the contribution model for that yet because sort of the list in the get have repo as
or shipping in the box there's talk on obvious
so extensibility...extensibility as well coming up that will smith is doing.
I think you should if you're interested in that you should go to that because while
...specific extensibility for the tasks
are is what it is the way you packaging deliver those
for consumption will be very heavily obviously based on that whole extensibility model so that will be interesting for
...as that comes around...as I mentioned the implementation
right now is on the windows side you implement your task is partial...
So, you can you can just you throw our...script maybe have some command let's in a
...just put those in the zip file and there
you go and you can run that you havewe give you access to something called the
distribute task context which has a bunch of other data and methods on
it you can use for doing sort of more interesting integrations and you can do from just a...script and,
then on the job on the across platforms size actually javascript.
Some interesting ...about whether or not we kind of sort of unify
all that around probably javascript but we'll see over time.
Of course don't hide your log look I just want to see what out what the output is there so,
I can I can be but my problem.
So, z...actually try to...for...controllers.
Anybody have problems the fact that...control only...collection,
yeah, so, we fix that.
So, architecturally new build stuff run side-by-side was able builds that means when you upgrade
to...fs twenty fifteen all your controllers keep on working even your twenty ten
controllers keep working so, those are there if you happen to have some twenty ten
controllers force building on windows xp which is primarily why people have those departing
you're twenty twelve controllers keep working and the...twenty thirteen
...keep working and then of course you can add new twenty fifteen ones...twenty fifteen
ones if you like to but they're still there so we didn't break anything from that perspective.
However, with the new system.
We significantly change the way it works we got rid of that physical
comptroller agent model on the surface that's kind of
a nice model for certain things but it brings up a lot of problems like if I have the single
controller in the primary way I connect to tf sss of the collection you sort end up
with one-to-one mapping you also...problem of the controller's not highly...anybody
lost controller that's got like fifty agents on it a whole bunch of builds running and they all get killed,
yeah, that's a huge pay so we fix that problem.
So, agents work.
In pool's pools are defined at the deployment level so
...to fs server with a bunch of applications years if you're using...highly available
...you can go to the server control panel and all pop over to
machine and show you that you can define multiple pools administrator can by the
fault the team foundation administrators the sort of server admins have access to create
pools there's a group you can be added to that gives you the ability to create
pools at the server level but nothing else so, you know,
longer have to give somebody kind of pretty high privileges just to manage the
build machines further once you create a...you
could actually assign administrators at the pool level so you if you're work on
...adamantly fs and you've got a bunch of different teams you want to give them different
pools you can assign somebody from that team the ability to administer that pool and only that
pool so they can add agents...move edge to it manage that but they can't do anything else with it so the
security...for the management a whole lot better and the x as I mentioned the agents rx copy deployed
...auto updated from the server so basically you there's a button on the
adnan page where you download the agent uns of the file you run a
...script configure it it's up and running and from then on
...just auto updates itself as a server updates.
There's a picture...like this.
This is a really crazy one where I've got machines that I'm sharing with
they work side-by-side so I can have a machine with...agent control running on I can add one
the noob new...same machine no problem there's no interaction so,
I have a lot of different lot of different capabilities there.
Security so, I mention that scoping on the
build definition each build when we run runs
...its own process as anybody run into a fun phenomenon with
the current agent where file handle gets left open for some reason
...the build host process and you have no idea why, yeah,
that's a problem too because builds do a lot of things I mean they write files they read files they create
...for files I mean they're really interesting operation so what we do is every
build...gets run gets a new worker process that the agent spends up.
And, it runs that build and when it when it's done it kills that worker process and creates a new
would for the next one so any state any environment variable set any
file handles open anything like that or completely contained that worker process so
things should be much more robust from that perspective and we've seen that internally...our own usage and,
then of course I mention the...administration delegation and then each
...also gets its own unique access token this time limited
so the build starts up we create a connection back to the server for writing logs
and drops and things like that back-up that is only held within that worker process that's not available
as an environment variable is available to tasks so-if you have a task
you've created you can you can get access to that connection we sort of
view that as a trusted part of the system but just somebody running some eggs the running so
...our...script or whatever doesn't have the ability to easily create a connection back to
...get access to those credentials so we think we significantly improved the overall
...so really quick ...part back here?
We have and I'll show you sort of the administration.
So, as I mentioned so this is actually is a...so instance I have I
...to pool's listed so one of them is the hosted pool.
And, it's so, this is...sort of a special pool because it's one we provide...are...provision via
...and while you won't see this feature
right away later on a year will enable us that you actually
to agents I happen to have to ages listed here so currently today and hosted service
it's a little difficult to run builds multiple builds because you get serialized behind each other
with the new architecture we're going to be able to enable feature where you can
...multiple agents in your in hosted
...you can actually potential uses a much more real a solution.
But, my default pool here that I created for expand that I can see I've got an agent
pool administration group and an agent full-service accounts group which I happen to be
in both of those but that's fine but, I can then go and I could create additional
...I could do new pool here because I happen to be global admin I
could delegate administration and if I want to install the age and I can just click on that and
download the agent and configured on my machine and I'm off and running?
And, then once I've done that so if you think about...instance
you probably have multiple collections...creative pool at the deployment level
at the server level you can then say which collections can use that
...so not every collection can use every
pool by default so once you go do that if you go to the
are collection administration page there's a build tab here.
And, I can see a list of we call them...at the collection levels...they are this is where the
builds q but I can see that in this collection I actually happen to have both
...but, I can only have one and somebody else might have a different one
so you actually so the ability to manager build
resources to balance your build resources across many different machine many different teams
reader collections is significantly are improved under this new architecture.
That is kind of the end of the overview so.
Download the...take it for...
The your via so accounts will get the new build.
Probably will still be build preview when you first see it but shortly thereafter
will switch just be the build tab so the build tab will be the
do experience with both new builds able builds all the
web editing everything in your accounts and a couple of weeks so we have a deployment coming up.
In two weeks so shortly thereafter you will see...all these new features of course you can
see the rc so-if that's it there.
The questions.
...the mic please or...sorrowful so they can get...the video.
I didn't see but I was hoping...of gated builds.
gated that's an interesting question so obviously the...system had actual gated
builds for...with the new one of the new features coming with
...pptx twenty fifteen so what we call this lease...get this...requests and then as part of
...requests we have policies and one of those policies is build
so in the same feature will eventually come for...right so with the
...request you can set up of say hey from branch feature
...a master nobody can push the master right you push...feature bridge to get
...master you have to open up a poorer question that has to be code reviewed and then I have a
build definition has to be running past before that could be let through so
that is the same kind of thing is gated though a little bit different because gated as you think about it...
of ec does not really work forget at all we currently do not have traditional gated for
...vc yet but a very similar policy method probably based around
shelves sets which is actually how gated works will be coming and that's how we're going to implement gated
in this new system versus the way we do it today is a little bit strange because
...kind of reject the check in and then you shelving create some interesting problem so this new extensible
system will mean that instead of just having potentially one gate on any
checking you can have multiple gates I think which will be as much more flexible for you.
Other questions...
Is it still possible to get code coverage data yes okay, yeah,
so, I mean the same the same data exists for tessa code coverage
...run it's pushed up you just don't see it there because
as part of at the point of this deployment the api...rest api forgetting code coverage data
what complete yetthey're actually checked in yesterday I think so,
you'll see that so cinco coverage okay is that just csharp resents
...like cobertura a coverage reports so currently it is just based on the
are code coverage but we I have a very
...given strong feedback to the team that sort of that coverage xml or the cobertura sort of
rough standard needs to be supported as well so I expect to see that at some point?
The question about retention policies yes with their
...add a feature of retention by size.
Potential by size like I've got a...space
okay keep it up until that point I see that's interesting that's
...I've thought about it but thanks for that I'll take that...redskins like, you know,
you do a lot more...closer...makes sense...
Does the cross platform a tools you demoed on the
...support patrick sort of?
Yes, so, we can...a couple different ways they're actually the so the
cordova tools for visual studio there'swhen all of this goes
out live we have a really great tutorial and how to...and yes you can build your one
app with that cordova platform on windows in on
...one package...for each platform?
...it's actually really cool so I work I work pretty closely with the guys who worked on that and we
...sure that was a good experience if we need to use
a compiler that's not supported by one of the tasks, for example, tci firmware
compiler something along those lines how difficult is it to get that
...and it will be possible to do that in a hosted pool.
So, it depends how do you what your makes so mean you have
the compiler the make system what makes system the used to run that compiler I don't know.
So, ... there's lots of different ones msi...build a make system
...maven those kinds of things are make system so typically compilers
...via some sort of make system and then
...integrating that is very easy because all of our stuff if you look at the
opensource repositories basically...boils down to taking some parameters building up a
command line and launching that command line and from the standpoint the hosted pool if
your compiler is deployable via some for ex copy mechanism then yes
that would work we don't have current support for
like installing custom software that requires elevated privileges or anything like that.
Is there still the two-hundred-and-fifty five character path...samoa?
yes, I there's not a lot...there's really nothing I can do about that we do have some interesting we actually there
was a very interesting bug that came across a couple weeks back because ...
dash which is a node module create some very interesting very long very
deep paths so we've done work to make sure we can at least delete those
via the native windows api is but we can't support, you know, really building more than
to fifty-five because so many tools just don't supported on windows.
Yes, so, I saw with...deploy it
had the capability for what looked like web deploy and running of arbitrary commands on the target
...are any build tasks available for say if we
reproducing msi packages or even
...based installs or anything else like that so we don't have anything out-of-the-box but if you
go to if you go look at the video the diamond session that those some of the new deployment stuff coming there's
better I mean in the end...can you get on to the box to run that msi
it's really just msi exec against that...
So, there's no reason there couldn't be it would be very easy to write something that does that
but it's not something we've done...yet out-of-the-box but it's a good idea.
Exactly, yeah.
So,...the example was...our...script that just does start process
and goes so we use extensively could you...
hand lab management zero it test build the...how does that has
...so are you so which part
specifically well there's a traditional test build the case that in the
old visual studio with this one how does that has that correlate ok sothe ok,
the old the example template there
is loudly time of the lab template that we're talking about that's correct, yeah,
so, we at this point there's not a direct correlation some of the
release management stuff that's coming in the future actually is the future of doing those sorts of
operations that will be much better for that the one thing you did see is we have
the distributed test running so you can sort of point that a bunch of machines
...go run these tests on that machines but the exact equivalent to
lab management is not fully integrated yet but it is on the train that's coming great?